connextra.com 2018-06-29

# Privacy Policy - Genius Sports

Genius Sports Group Limited (“Genius Sports”, “the Company”, “we”, “us” or “our”) is committed to protecting the privacy of our clients and users of our website. We will ensure that any information you submit to us or that we collect, through whatever method, is used only for the purposes set out in this policy.

For the purpose of the EU General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (“GDPR”) and national laws implementing GDPR, the data controller is Genius Sports Group Limited, a company registered in England and Wales under company number 09706742, our registered office is 25a Soho Square, London W1D 3QR. References in this Privacy Policy to our Group of companies is to the parent company of Genius Sports Group Ltd and to other trading subsidiaries of Genius Sports Group Ltd.

Through this Privacy Policy we aim to inform you about the types of personal data we collect from users, the purposes for which we use the data and the ways in which the data is handled. We also aim to satisfy the obligation of transparency under the GDPR.

This website ([www.geniussports.com](http://www.geniussports.com/)), (“the Site”) is operated by Genius Sports.

This policy (together with our Site’s [terms of use](https://www.geniussports.com/website-terms-of-use/), and any other documents referred to in them) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

We are keen to strike a fair balance between your personal privacy and ensuring that you obtain full value from the products and services (“the Services”) that we may provide to you.

The Company is registered with the [Information Commissioner’s Office](https://ico.org.uk/) as a data controller, with registration number ZA198905.

### Right to Object

You have a legal right to object at any time to:

  * use of your personal information for direct marketing purposes; and
  * processing of your personal information which is based on our legitimate interests, unless there are compelling legitimate grounds for our continued processing.

### Information We May Collect

When people visit [www.geniussports.com](http://www.geniussports.com/) we use a third party service, Google Analytics provided by Google, Inc., to collect anonymous information about visitor behaviour patterns. This service sets a cookie in order to evaluate use of those services and compile a report for us. You can [opt-out of Google Analytics cookies](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

We offer a contact form for you to request additional product or service information. This form asks for first name, last name, company name and email address.

Job applications can be submitted through the Site. We will collect personal details including: name, email address, telephone number, salary expectations, visa information, notice period and CV. You can submit your contact details and CV via our website or directly to one of our Talent Acquisition Team. You can apply for a specific advertised position or for consideration by our Talent Acquisition Team for new positions as they arise.

No other personal information is collected during a visit to our website.

### How We Use Your Personal Information

If you complete an enquiry form, we will contact you by email so that we can discuss the products or services in which you have indicated an interest. Data entered through the form will be added to our Customer Relationship Management system.

If you submit a job application through the Site, your CV and contact details will be stored in the Talent Acquisition Team’s database and retained for the duration of your application. Application details will be held for up to two years after completion except where retention is required by law (for example candidates from the US, whose details will be held for seven years). Your personal information may be passed to or accessed by Genius Sports Group companies both inside and outside the European Economic Area for such purposes as to offer relevant job opportunities to you. You may withdraw your permission for your data to be processed outside the EU by making a request to our team using the Contact Us details below. A full list of the companies in our Group can be found here.

You can update your CV at any time by simply submitting a new CV. Your old CV will automatically be archived providing the submission details remain the same.

### How We Share Your Personal Information

Genius Sports will not share your personal information with other parties except to provide a service you have requested, such as a newsletter, or insofar as we may be required to do so by law.

### Trusted Third Parties

Genius Sports works with a number of trusted third parties to provide services to you.

The Genius Sports website is hosted by Pagely ([privacy policy](https://pagely.com/legal/privacy-policy/)), a company based in Tucson, Arizona.

The sales teams use Microsoft Dynamics and Office 365 to store and process contact details submitted through the commercial enquiry form.

The Talent Acquisition team uses Microsoft Office 365, SharePoint and OneDrive services to store and process applications and contact details. Microsoft PowerBI is used to report on job applications and received data.

We will only share your personal information with trusted third parties retained to provide services that you have requested or for our legitimate business purposes, such as CRM, IT or professional support services.

### Transfer of Information Outside the EEA

Under the Data Protection Act 2018, we are required to tell you if we transfer or intend to transfer your personal data to countries outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). We only transfer such information outside the EEA if:

  1. Your product or service enquiry is are best handled by one of our companies located outside the EEA:

Genius Sports Media Inc.  
100 Wilshire Boulevard, Suite 940  
Santa Monica, CA 90401  
USA

Genius Sports Inc.  
404 5th Ave  
New York, NY 10018  
USA

A full list of the companies in our Group can be found [here](https://www.geniussports.com/contact/).

  1. The service you have requested, such as a newsletter, is delivered through a trusted third-party (like MailChimp) located outside the EEA.
  2. You have submitted a job application through the Site; applications will be reviewed by our Talent Acquisition team in Los Angeles and other offices.

We apply equal rigour to the security of data held and processed by us or on our behalf outside of the EEA. We have taken steps to ensure that our subsidiaries and affiliates and those who process data on our behalf enter into the standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission, to safeguard the personal information which is transferred to and from the European Economic Area and beyond.

Because some of our servers are located in the USA, transfer of all our data outside the EEA is necessary to enable us to operate the Site. To the extent that any personal information is provided to third parties outside the EEA, or who will access the information from outside the EEA, we take steps to ensure that approved safeguards are in place, such as the approved standard contractual clauses or the EU/US Privacy Shield.

### The Legal Basis for Processing your Personal Information

The Genius Sports website gathers and processes your personal data only if you actively give it to us. Under the GDPR, the legal basis for process your personal information is Consent; you have asked us to provide a service (such as a newsletter), to contact you using the details you have submitted or to consider your for a position within the Group.

To withdraw your consent for activities related to sales or a job application, please contact Genius Sports.

### Disclosure of Your Information

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

  1. if Genius Sports’ or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets;
  2. in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets;
  3. if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, this includes co-operation with any investigation carried out by a body investigating criminal or fraudulent behaviour;
  4. in order to enforce or apply our terms of website use or other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of us, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with companies and organisations for the purposes of age verification, fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

If this happens, we will notify you of such event.

### Your Rights on the Information We Hold About You

You have rights regarding any personal information we hold about you. Details of these rights and how to exercise them are set out below. We will require evidence of your identity before we are able to act on your request.

#### Right of Access

You have the right at any time to ask us for a copy of the personal information about you that we hold. Where we have good reason, and if the GDPR permits, we can refuse your request for a copy of your personal information, or certain elements of the request. If we refuse your request or any element of it, we will provide you with our reasons for doing so.

#### Right of Correction or Completion

If personal information we hold about you is not accurate, out of date or incomplete, you have a right to have the data rectified, updated or completed. You can let us know by contacting us [link to Contact section].

#### Right of Erasure

In certain circumstances, you have the right to request that personal information we hold about you is erased e.g. if the information is no longer necessary for the purposes for which it was collected or processed or our processing of the information is based on your consent and there are no other legal grounds on which we may process the information.

#### Right to object to or restrict processing

In certain circumstances, you have the right to object to our processing of your personal information by contacting us [link to Contact section]. For example, if we are processing your information on the basis of our legitimate interests and there are no compelling legitimate grounds for our processing which override your rights and interests. You also have the right to object to use of your personal information for direct marketing purposes.

You may also have the right to restrict our use of your personal information, such as in circumstances where you have challenged the accuracy of the information and during the period where we are verifying its accuracy.

#### Right of Data Portability

In certain instances, you have a right to receive any personal information that we hold about you in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. You can ask us to transmit that information to you or directly to a third party organisation.

The above right exists only in respect of personal information that:

  * you have provided to us previously; and
  * is processed by us using automated means.

While we are happy for such requests to be made, we are not able to guarantee technical compatibility with a third party organisation’s systems. We are also unable to comply with requests that relate to personal information of others without their consent.

You can exercise any of the above rights by contacting us using any of the methods in the Contact section below.

Most of the above rights are subject to limitations and exceptions. We will provide reasons if we are unable to comply with any request for the exercise of your rights.

#### Consent

To the extent that we are processing your personal information based on your consent, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. You can do this by using the details in the Contact section below.

### Regulatory and Law Enforcement Agencies

As noted above, if we receive a request from a regulatory body or law enforcement agency, and if permitted under GDPR and other laws, we may disclose certain personal information to such bodies or agencies.

### How Long We Will Hold Your Information

We will retain your personal information only for the time necessary to provide the Services we perform for you, or stated by the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy. In particular, we will store certain categories of your personal information for the following periods of time:

**Category of Personal Data** | **Storage time period**  
---|---  
Contact details for sales enquiries | 2 years after last contact  
Email address for newsletter | Until you unsubscribe  
Job applications and CVs | 2 years (and 7 years for US applicants)  
  
### Use of Cookies and Tracking Technology

Our site uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our Web site. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our site and also allows us to improve our site. You can find full details of our cookie usage in our [Cookie Policy](https://www.geniussports.com/cookie-policy/).

We only track users’ behaviour on our Site and we do not have access to your behaviour on other websites other than in relation to how you were referred to the Site (e.g. through another site or a search term).

### Security

We respect your information and have put in place measures to ensure the security of the information we collect and store about you. We are committed to protecting your personal data from unauthorised disclosure and/or access including through the use of network and database security measures (though these cannot always guarantee the security of any data which is collected and stored).

### Complaints

If you are unhappy about our use of your personal information, you can contact us using the details in the Contact section below. You are also entitled to lodge a complaint with the UK Information Commissioner’s Office using any of the below contact methods:

**Telephone**  
0303 123 1113

**Website**  
<https://ico.org.uk/concerns/>

**Post**  
Information Commissioner’s Office  
Wycliffe House  
Water Lane  
Wilmslow  
Cheshire  
SK9 5AF

If you live or work outside the UK or you have a complaint concerning our activities outside the UK, you may prefer to lodge a complaint with a different supervisory authority.

### Changes to our Privacy Policy

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page.

### Further Information on Data Protection and Personal Privacy

If you have any enquiries or if you would like to contact us about our processing of your personal information, including to exercise your rights as outlined above, please contact us by one of the methods listed below. When you contact us, we will ask you to verify your identity.

**Contact name**  
Scott Simpson, Data Protection Officer

**Telephone**  
+44 (0) 20 7851 4060

**Email**  

**Post**  
25a Soho Square  
London  
W1D 3QR
